# Kamran Amini

## Senior Software Engineer at ActiveVideo BV

High Skilled Migrant in Netherlands

Parnassusweg 999, Amsterdam 1082LZ

+31 (0) 611060215 Email: kam.cpp@gmail.com Github: github.com/kamcpp

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamcpp

#### **SUMMARY**

With over 14 years of professional experience in various fields of software development, I've dedicated my past few years to creating cloud-based distributed systems. While always been a key contributor to the overall architecture and design, considering requirements like security, availability, robustness, fault tolerance, etc, I have always had a strong will to be part of the development team and code some of the critical key components. Hence, backed by my academic studies in computer science, I have had the pleasure of learning by coding and seeing serious corner cases and bugs in action. I have used many programming languages, but system languages like C, C++, Golang, and Rust have always been amongst the most loved ones. As part of my career, I have always tried to keep an eye on the DevOps side of things, therefore, I have gained invaluable experience in scripting and configuring Bash, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, AWS resources, etc. I do love start-ups and the mindset around raising one, so Javascript and NodeJS technology is among the game-changers in that field and I've had the chance to use them extensively in different projects. Moreover, during the past few years, I have gathered a deep understanding of distributed ledgers and blockchains, so I have worked with various blockchain startups to develop their on-chain complex financial logic (smart contracts) using Solidity.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: C++ (14, 17, 20) C Golang Rust JS (ES5, ES6) Java (11+) Python (2, 3)
- Blockchain Development: Solidity (EVM chains) Solana web3 (ethers.js, web3.js) Hardhat
- Architecture Concepts: ACID CAP In-memory and Dist. caches Distributed key-value stores Replication Fault tolerance Leader election Dist. locks Dist. file systems Streaming Micro-batching CQRS Event Sourcing Message Queues Green threads Event loops and async programming Load balancers
- Data Storage: PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB Redis Dist. ledgers (blockchains)
- Kubernetes: kubect1 k9s Helm Kustomize Configuring resources such as ingress, pod, deployment, replica set, secrets, pod security policies, pod security admission (PSA) as of 1.25 Migration from earlier versions to 1.23 and 1.25
- Amazon AWS: awcli eksctl Configuring resources such as EC2 instances, EBS volumes, EFS, S3, ALBs, EKS, IAM, etc
- Serialization & RPC: Protobuf gRPC ZeroMQ Thrift JSON over REST SOAP Java RMI XMLRPC
- Standards: SUS and POSIX PKCS standards JavaEE (JPA, JSM, EJB, Java Servlets, JAX-WS, JAX-RS, etc) RFCs (ASN.1, IP, TCP, UDP, DNS, HTTP, CMS, etc), ERCs (20, 721, 1155, 165, 2981, 2535, ...)
- Cryptography: OpenSSL Symmetric algos (DES, 3DES, AES) Asymmetric algos (RSA, ECC, DH) SSL PKI (CA, Digital Signature, PKCS certs, HSMs and Cyrpto. Tokens) Wrap Keys Key Derivation Algorithms Hash algos MAC algos Error Detection (Crypto. Hashes), studying for CISSP certificate
- Computer Networks: OSI & Internet Protocol Suite, Packet Switching, Error Detection & Correction (Checksum, CRC, ARQ, FEC), L3 protocols (ICMP, IP) L4 protocols (UDP, TCP) Socket Programming L3 programming (1ibpcap, JNetPcap) Wireshark analysis Penetration Testing tcpdump
- Kernel Development: Linux Modules Linux System Calls
- Machine Learning: CUDA Dev. Tensorflow (C++ & Python) OpenCV (C, C++, Python) Supervised & Unsupervised Learning Reinforced Learning Deep Learning Locality Sensitive Hashes Iris Code Gabor filter Feature Selection & Extraction

## **CAREER**

## ★ ActiveVideo BV

Senior Software Engineer (April. 2019 - Feb. 2023)

Netherlands, Hilversum
• CloudTV: TODO
• AppCloud: TODO

• Member of Tech Council: TODO

• Founding member of Security Guild: TODO

• C++17 (g++, clang) - Python - AWS - Kubernetes (EKS) - TODO

## ★ TomTom BV

Senior Software Engineer (Sept. 2017 - March. 2019)

Netherlands, Amsterdam

- Expert Software Consultant from Modis B.V.
- NavKit Free Text Search Engine, Navkit Worker REST Services, POI Info Services
- C++11 (g++, clang) Java SE JUnit Spring MVC JAXB Spring REST gdb Valgrind Clang ASAN & TSAN STL & Boost Google Test Protobuf Thrift Python Jenkins QuickBuild Docker- JIRA Fisheye Confluence Bitbucket Stash AWS/Azure based cloud

# **★** Jeppesen Systems (a Boeing subsidary)

Senior Software Engineer (Feb. 2017 - Aug. 2017)

Sweden, Gothenburg

- Manpower Application
- C++11 (g++) Python C#.NET gdb Valgrind (callgrind, massif) PDB STL & Boost Google Test XMLRPC Jenkins JIRA Fisheye Confluence

#### **★** Adro Co.

Senior Software Architect, Principal C++ Engineer textsl(Jun. 2016 - Jan. 2017)

Iran, Tehran

- Realtime Bidding (RTB) Engine
- C++ (g++) Python gdb Valgrind STL & Boost libuv Google Test Protobuf Jenkins Travis CI Docker JIRA Fisheye

# **★** Naeem Co.

Chief Technical Officer, Chief Software Architect (Apr. 2015 - Oct. 2016)

Iran, Tehran

- Projects: ePassport Issuance System Face Recognition System, Biometric Identification Sys.
- Crypto.: OpenSSL PKCS (1, 7, 10, 11, 12) ICAO MRTD standards HSM Key Mgmt. PKCS11 Tokens
- Stack: C (gcc) C++ (g++) Java SE Java EE Spring MVC Wildfly Tomcat Python gdb Valgrind STL & Boost wxWdigets Qt Google Test Jenkins Docker vSphere Proxmox Gluster Cassandra Redmine GitLab

# **★** Sharif CERT Center

Software Engineer (Dec. 2011 - Jun. 2013)

Iran, Tehran

- Botnet Detection System Sinkhole DDNS as a FreeBSD module
- C++ (g++) Java SE Perl gdb JConsole Valgrind STL & Boost Swing Redmine

# **Technical authorship**

- Extreme C: My first book was published in October 2019 by Packt Publication.
- Linux Two-Step Authentication with Rust: A liveProject published by Manning Publications that walks through the students and makes them able to use Rust to develop a two-step verification system for authentication services.

## FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Persian (Native), English (Fluent), French (A1), Dutch (A2)

# **EDUCATION**

• 2017 - Present

The Open University

**Bachelor of Science in Physics (Astronomy and Planetary Science)** 

• 2004 - 2008

University of Isfahan

Isfahan, Iran

**Bachelor of Software Engineering** 

# PERSONAL INTERESTS

- **Physics and Astronomy**: Cosmology, Astronomy, Quantum Physics, Quantum Mechanics, Particle Physics, Special and General Relativity, Theory of Everything, Photonics.
- Mathematics: Linear and Abstract Algebra, Probability Theory, Information Theory
- Cryptography: Information Security, Network Security, Security Algorithms, Quantum Information Theory, Quantum Key Distribution, Quantum Cryptography
- Philosophy: Western Philosophy, Sociology, Economics, Politics and Humanities
- **Telecommunications**: Modulation, Multiplexing, Codes, Telecommunication circuits, Photonics and optical fibers, IEEE 802.3 Protocols, Information Theory, Coding Theory, Computer Networks, etc